Okay, everybody. Cake time!
好了  各位  蛋糕时间
Thank god. I really have to study.
老天  我真的得去学习
Oh, sweetheart, can't you just take a minute to enjoy it?
亲爱的  你就不能抽出点时间享用吗
It's your birthday.
这可是你的生日啊
You put too much pressure on yourself.
你给自己施加太多压力了
I remember my sweet 16.
我还记得我16岁那年
I wanted a theme party.
我想要个主题派对
"Moonstruck" had just come out, but I hadn't, so --
《月色撩人》刚刚上映  但我还没出柜
No stories, no time --
别讲故事  没时间听
S.A.T.s.
我是要考大学入学考试的人啊
Here we go, everybody.
来吧  各位
Wait, wait.
等等  等等
We all know why we're here.
我们都知道在庆祝什么
- Ay, honey, you missed one. - I know!
-亲爱的  你落下了一根  -我知道
I know I missed one! I'm not an idiot!
我知道我落下了一根  我不是傻子
There! Happy?!
这样  开心了吧
- You're being a little... - Obstreperous?!
-你有点...  -失控是吗
Recalcitrant?! Truculent?!
顽抗  还是野蛮
I was gonna say "Cray-cray."
我本来想说"神经兮兮"
Alex, sweet...
艾丽克斯  亲爱的
I really need to focus!
我真的得集中精神
There is a 16-year-old science prodigy
有个16岁的科学天才
studying cancer research at Johns Hopkins!
在约翰・霍普金斯大学做癌症研究
16! What am I doing?!
16岁  瞧瞧我在干什么
I'm eating cake!
我在吃蛋糕
No, no, no.
别这样  别这样
Cake! Cake! Cake!
蛋糕  蛋糕  蛋糕
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
■
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译 禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
Alex might be a little bit fragile after last night,
艾丽克斯在昨晚过后  可能会有点脆弱
so let's try to be sensitive.
所以我们得小心对待她
Oh, believe me -- I am going to be
相信我  从现在起
nothing but nice to Alex from now on.
我都会对她耐心又友好
If she snaps and goes on a rampage,
如果她哪天突然崩溃  实施暴行
who do you think she's coming for first?
你觉得她会最先找上谁
She's not going on a rampage.
她不会实施暴行的
I bet she'd let me live. She likes me.
我赌她会留我一命  她喜欢我
I'm just gonna say it -- I never trusted her.
坦白说  我从不信任她
Oh, everybody just be normal.
大家都正常一点就行了
We're gonna treat her exactly the way we usually do.
我们要像平时那样对她
And there she is.
她来了
- Hi, pretty girl. - How'd you sleep?
-美女  -你睡得怎么样
- Fine. - Your hair looks super-soft, Al.
-不错  -你的头发看起来超柔软  小艾
And is that a great new sweater? Love!
那是新的毛衣吗  超爱
Dad, can you hand me the butter knife?
老爸  你能把黄油刀递给我吗
No!
不行
Haley, Luke, upstairs, please.
海莉  卢克  请上楼去
Thank you.
谢谢
So, about my meltdown.
好吧  谈谈我昨晚的失控
- Who? - What meltdown?
-谁  -什么失控
I want to see a therapist. I did some research.
我想去看心理医生  我查了一下
Dr. Gregory Clark -- highly recommended,
格雷戈里・克拉克医生  超高推荐度
specializes in teenagers, and is covered by our insurance.
专治青少年  在我们的医保范围内
I booked a double session with him today.
我预约了今天找他看两个钟
And since you guys have the open house,
既然你们今天要参加学校开放日
I will be taking the bus.
我自己坐公交去
- Okay. - That sounds good.
-好  -听起来不错
She's like a self-cleaning oven.
她简直像个自动清洁炉
Check it out.
快看看
I'm rockin' the old school for the open house today.
我今天要以复古造型亮相开放日
I'm gonna put the "Fizz" back in "Phys Ed."
我要为体育课重新注入活力
I love it -- all of it.
我喜欢  全都喜欢
- Really? - Yeah.
-真的吗  -当然
Because I want to make a good impression today.
因为我今天想给家长们留下个好印象
I want to be the teacher all the parents are talking about.
我想成为所有家长谈论的对象
Well, that explains the socks.
是啊  难怪穿这袜子
What?
什么
There's a caste system at school --
学校里有一种等级制度
Academic teachers at the top, gym teachers at the bottom.
学术教师在顶层  体育教师在底层
It's offensive and disrespectful.
真的很讨厌  也很无礼
They treat us like we're lunch ladies.
他们像对待服务员一样对待我们
Hey, there, neighbor.
你好啊  邻居
- It's Asher, right? - Yeah.
-是亚瑟  对吧  -没错
Um, I just wanted to let you know --
我就是想告诉你
I think there might be something
我觉得你们家的空调
- wrong with your air conditioner. - Oh, really?
-可能坏了  -是吗
Yeah, I mean, it just seems to be running a lot,
是啊  好像总是开着
even when it's, uh, kind of cool outside.
即便屋外还挺凉快的
No, no.
不是  不是
Um, my partner runs a little hot.
我家那位有点怕热
Not as hot as our planet.
那也没我们这个地球热
Sorry. I don't mean to be that guy.
抱歉  我没想那么刻薄
It's just, um, we're all in this together.
只是  我们都在一个星球上
Yeah, I drive a Prius, so...
是啊  我开的是普锐斯车  所以
And that's a nice little gesture.
这倒是个不错的态度
My car runs on reclaimed cooking oil.
我的车用的是回收的食用油
I have some literature, if you want it.
我有一些相关文章  可以借你看
That's okay. Save the paper.
不用了  省纸吧
I haven't printed anything since 2004.
我从2004年起就没有印过任何东西
I was gonna e-mail you.
我打算发电邮给你
On your power-hungry computer?
用你那高耗电的电脑吗
My entire house is solar-powered.
我整座房子都是用太阳能供电的
I sell energy back to the grid
我把电卖回给电网
and use that money to save polar bears.
然后用那笔钱救北极熊
I'm an environmental lawyer,
我是个环保律师
so, you know, I'm pretty green.
所以我也是非常环保[绿色]的
So is your lawn.
你的草地也是嘛
I went drought-tolerant --
我的庭院是抗干旱的
Succulents, indigenous plants, rock garden.
多肉植物  本地植物  岩石庭院
My other daddy says your yard looks like a litter box.
我另一个爸爸说你的庭院像猫砂箱
She's a cute kid.
她真是个可爱的孩子
I remember when she was in disposable diapers.
我还记得她穿一次性尿布时的样子
Are you ready?
你准备好了吗
Yeah.
好了
Why do you look like that when I look like this?
你穿这么漂亮干嘛  跟我不搭啊
My friends say it's because of your money.
我朋友说那是因为你有钱
No, I'm just saying why is she all dressed up
不  我是说  不过是个学校开放日
for a school open house?
干嘛盛装打扮
I want to impress Manny's history teacher.
我想给曼尼的历史老师留下深刻印象
I want Manny to go to Washington, D.C.
我想让曼尼去华盛顿
Yeah, Junior Congress.
是的  参加青少年国会
Only one kid in the whole grade gets picked to go.
整个年级只有一个名额
I think I can make a difference.
我觉得我能有所作为
Regular Congress can't even make a difference.
得了吧  真的国会都只是个摆设而已
Don't worry, Manny. I have it covered.
别担心  曼尼  包在我身上
You just go and enjoy your date.
你只管去好好约会吧
I have a date. It's no big deal.
我确实有个约会  没什么大不了
D-don't make a whole thing about it.
你不要大惊小怪
What did I do with my car keys?
我的车钥匙哪儿去了
I mean, we're just friends now,
我们还只是朋友而已
but I have a good feeling.
但我有很好的预感
I know -- don't get ahead of myself.
好吧  我知道不应该言之过早
Every time I put them down.
每次一放下都找不着了
What is her name?
她叫什么名字
Either Zoe or Piper.
要么是佐伊  要么就是派珀
How can you be going on a date and you don't know her name?
你怎么连约会对象的名字都不知道呢
This is where it gets interesting.
这就是有意思的地方啊
I seriously doubt that.
我深表怀疑
A few days ago, we almost let a girl come between us.
几天前我们差点因为一个女孩争风吃醋
- Who is she? - The new girl.
-那是谁  -新来的姑娘
- She's pretty. - Super-pretty.
-好漂亮  -美极了
Dibs.
我要了
What?! N-no. You can't call dibs.
什么  不  你不能这样
She's a human being with feelings,
她是个有情感的大活人
not the front seat.
这不是在抢前排座位
Then a miracle happened.
接着奇迹发生了
Twins -- each as pretty as the other.
双胞胎  一样的美丽动人
It's funny -- Luke and I don't usually
这很有趣  因为卢克和我一般
go for the same kind of girl.
不会看上同一类型的女孩
Yeah. I like to describe my type as "Gettable".
没错  我喜欢的类型是"容易上手型"
What are you doing, Tucker?
你在干什么  塔克
Oh, hey, Principal Brown.
你好啊  布朗校长
Do you know how other teachers drone on and on
你知道其他的老师总是给家长
to parents with their boring lectures?
讲那些枯燥无趣的老生常谈
Well, I thought I would go another way.
我觉得我可以另辟蹊径
Oh. Well, I don't like the sound of that at all.
听上去可不大妙
I think you will.
你一定会喜欢的
I'm gonna spice things up with a spirited game of dodgeball.
我打算来一堂躲避球课  活跃一下气氛
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no.
不要  千万不要  一百个不要
Okay, before you say "No"...
在你说"不要"之前
I already said "No."
我已经说了"不要"了
...let me show you my whole bit.
先看看我的全套构思
Howdy, folks.
你们好  伙计们
My name's Tucker.
我名字叫塔克
I'm the Sheriff of Dodge...ball.
是"多比"镇警官  其实是"躲避"球
"Laugh, laugh, laugh."
家长们会哄堂大笑
And then --
然后
No, no "then." No.
不  没有然后  不行
Have you seen the shape some of these folks are in?
你看到那些家长的身材了吗
We don't need a parent dropping dead in here.
我们可不想某个家长当场倒毙
Look, this is the "Dolphin Den."
这里是海豚湾体育馆
I am not renaming it
可没打算改名叫
the Harvey K. Mandelbaum memorial gym.
曼德尔鲍姆纪念馆
But I was gonna divide everybody up into
但我本来想把大家分成哈特菲尔德队
the Hatfield and McCoys.
和麦考伊队打比赛呢
Just no dodgeball.
不许打躲避球
Hello, Mr. Ingram.
你好  英格拉姆老师
I am Gloria Delgado-Pritchett,
我是歌洛莉亚・德尔加多・迪尔加多
Manny's mother.
曼尼的妈妈
Yes, of course.
没错  当然了
I just wanted to thank you so much.
我想好好感谢您
He thinks the world of you.
我儿子对您评价极高
You know, as a child of an immigrant,
作为移民的小孩
he can look at the world with such a fresh perspective.
您让他对世界有别具一格的新鲜看法
And talking about fresh,
提到"新鲜"
I brought you some empanadas.
我给你带了些墨西哥酥皮饺子
Subtle.
真有一套啊
Hey, Phil. Where's Claire?
菲尔  克莱尔呢
Oh, she's going to Alex's classes.
她去艾丽克斯的教室了
I'm doing Luke's.
我负责卢克这一边
I'm surprised to see you here.
你居然来了我很惊讶
Isn't your team playing today?
你的球队不是今天比赛吗
Yeah. Gloria made me come.
就是啊  但歌洛莉亚非要我来
I think I'm recording the game,
我设好了录像机
but, you know, you can never know.
但谁知道会发生什么意外情况
The last time, I got six hours of Bravo.
上次我录了六小时的Bravo电视台的节目
And who knows?
万事皆有可能
Maybe Manny's going to be the first Latino President.
保不准曼尼就是第一个拉丁裔总统呢
Hello, Mr. Ingram.
你好  英格拉姆老师
Dr. Donna Duncan,
我是唐娜・邓肯医生
Wesley's mom.
韦斯利的妈妈
Just brought you a little thank-you
一点小谢礼  不成敬意
for being his absolute favorite teacher ever.
因为您是我儿子最喜欢的老师
- Those cupcakes are so white. - Thank you.
-这些蛋糕够白的  -谢谢夸奖
Dr. Donna Duncan.
我是唐娜・邓肯医生
I'm Gloria.
我是歌洛莉亚
We've met several times.
我们见过几次
Oh, of course.
当然记得了
Mario's mom.
马里奥的妈妈
Manny.
是曼尼
And how is he fitting in now? Better?
他适应得怎么样  比以前好些吗
Anyway...
总之
Here she is.
我带了好东西
You brought a flask to an open house?
你带了个酒壶来学校开放日吗
You want some? It's Scotch.
想来点吗  苏格兰威士忌
No. Put it away.
不  拿远点
Don't be such a goody-goody.
别这么娘娘腔
Taste it. It's older than you are.
尝一口  这酒比你年纪还大
- I don't want any scotch. - Well, just smell it.
-我才不想喝威士忌  -那就闻一下
- Fine. - Mr. Dunphy, is that a flask?
-好  -邓菲先生  你拿的是酒壶吗
No. It is. It I--
不是  是  实际上
Uh, I was -- it's his.
我只是  是他的
No, it's not.
才不是我的
For the record, no alcohol is allowed on school premises.
提醒一下  严禁带酒来学校
For god's sake, Phil,
你太不象话了  菲尔
it's 2:00 in the afternoon.
这才下午两点而已
So, Alex, tell me why you're here.
艾丽克斯  跟我说说你为什么来这里
I had a little meltdown last night,
我昨晚有点情绪失控
and I'm afraid it'll happen again.
我害怕以后还会这样
But, this time, in the middle of the S.A.T or something.
但下次没准会发生在大学入学考试过程中
Why do you think you melted down?
那你为什么失控了呢
I'm stressed.
我压力山大啊
It's my junior year.
我已经高三了
Part of me feels like
我觉得可能是
the limbic system in my brain's a bit off.
我的大脑边缘系统有点儿失灵
That's a thing, right? I did some research.
有这么一种病  对吧  我做过调研
You know I charge the same
你知道就算你自我诊断了
even if you diagnose yourself?
我也照旧收钱  对吧
I'm just trying to move this along.
我只想提高下效率
I have a lot to do.
我还有很多事要做
Well, uh, this is a process.
治疗是讲究过程的
You know, it takes some time.
需要花些时间
What -- what are you thinking?
你在想什么
- Nothing. - No, no. Go ahead. Tell me.
-没什么  -没事  直说好了
That maybe you're not up for this.
我觉得你可能帮不上我
I mean, no offense.
无意冒犯
You're just a lot older than you look on your website.
只不过你看起来比网站上老很多
Did you even have S.A.T.s when you were in high school
你上学那个年代有大学入学考试
or Asian kids?
或是亚裔学生吗
Oh, no. no, no, no.
那倒没有
But there were other things I worried about --
但也有其他事情让我很担心
Spanish inquisition,
比如西班牙宗教法庭
sailing off the edge of the world,
出海寻找世界尽头
learning how to understand fire.
还要学习火到底是什么东西
Sorry.
抱歉
- You mind if we try something? - What?
-不如我们换一种方式  -什么
Just do me a favor.
就当帮我的忙了
Take a deep breath.
深吸一口气
Great.
很好
Now... what's on your mind?
此时此刻  你在想什么
Well... I just remembered that I forgot
我才想起来在离家之前
to charge my computer before I left
我忘了给电脑充上电了
and that I have to get new index cards before Monday.
而且我该在周一前买新的索引卡
Hopefully they don't run out of the blue ones,
希望还有蓝色的
because, for some reason, those help me study better.
因为不知为何蓝色的能帮助我学习
Maybe it's because they're easier to read
也许是因为它们读起来容易些
or maybe my prescription's getting worse.
也许是因为我的药方不管用了
I should probably make an appointment with the eye doctor.
我或许该去找我的眼科医生检查一下
Also, should I get a job this summer
还有  我这个暑假是不是该找个工作
or would an internship look better on my application?
实习经验会不会有利于我的申请
And what is up with Hillary?
再有  希拉里到底是怎么了
Is she going to run or not?
她到底要不要竞选
I mean, I feel like she'd totally understand
我觉得她应该完全理解
the feeling of being overwhelmed,
被别人风头压在下面的感觉
but also like you're not doing enough at the same time.
但同时又觉得她没有尽最大努力
Hey, Nina, how's Sanjay?
你好  妮娜  你家桑杰怎么样
Oh, great. Thanks.
很好  谢谢关心
He's just dealing with the S.A.T.s and the A.C.T.s.
他在准备入学考试和大学测验
And that merit scholarship application
还有那个荣誉奖学金申请
everyone's so stressed about.
每个人都在努力争取
What -- what application?
什么  什么申请
Let's begin by talking about the A.P. Physics test,
我们从物理考试开始说起吧
which, as you know, takes place on...
你们都知道  这门考试安排在
May 21st.
5月21日
With Luke and Haley,
卢克和海莉自理能力差
I'm on top of everything because they aren't.
所以我要为他们安排好所有事
But Alex is so self-sufficient,
但是艾丽克斯是那么的自立
I just sort of put it in cruise control.
我就撒手让她自己干了[调到自动巡航模式]
I've fallen asleep at the wheel,
我在方向盘那儿睡着了
and now my little genius is covered in cake.
结果现在我的小天才往自己身上抹蛋糕
Now, a list of practice tests I recommend
下面是我推荐学生
the students take before then
在考试前做的习题
3a, 4c, 12a through "f,"
3a  4c  12a一直到f题
18d, 19a, 23c,
18d  19a  23c
24g, 25h, 26a...
24g  25h  26a
Meanwhile, a great artist like Bob Dylan
同时  像鲍勃・迪伦这样伟大的艺术家
would get voted off in the first round, which --
会在第一轮就出局
If you wet the end,
如果你把吸管的一端弄湿
it will stick to his face.
就会粘在他脸上
You're a genius.
你真是个天才
Piper, that's rude.
派珀  那样做太无礼了
You know, Manny, in chorus,
曼尼  我们合唱队会唱
we sing "Blowin' in the wind."
《随风飘荡》这首歌
Now that's blowin' in the wind.
这才叫做"随风飘荡"
You're funny, Luke.
你真风趣  卢克
Manny and I need to use the restroom.
曼尼和我要去趟洗手间
We do?
是吗
You've got to switch with me.
你得跟我换换对象
What? No, we can't do that.
什么  不行  我们不能那样做
They're twins. They'll never notice.
她们是双胞胎  是不会发觉的
You realize we're not twins, right?
你知道我们俩不是双胞胎吧
Special dollhouse delivery for Lily!
莉莉的娃娃屋特快专递来啦
It's here, it's here!
来啦  来啦
I think you're going to love it.
你绝对会爱上它的
I spent so many hours playing with this when I was your age.
我像你这么大的时候  整天都在玩这个
Yeah, me too.
我也是
Hey, quick, turn off your car.
快点把车熄火
Why? It's in park, I think.
怎么了  在停车模式上呢  我觉得
I have a judgey green neighbor.
我有个邻居是环保人士
He had the nerve to come over here
他竟然有胆子跑过来
and tell me that I'm not green enough.
跟我说我不够环保
Shut up! You're super-green.
不会吧  你超级环保的
Thank you. I'm -- I'm recycling a dollhouse.
谢了  我回收利用了个娃娃屋
I even recycled a child.
我甚至还"回收利用"了个孩子
- Didn't you win some award? - Yes, yes.
-你不是还赢了个奖吗  -对的对的
The state bar association award for sustained excellence
州律师协会奖  为了表彰在环境法方面
in the field of environmental...
做出长期卓越的贡
yeah, yeah, yeah. That's the one.
对对对  就是这个
...law. There was one word left.
献  还有一个字没说完呢
You didn't have to cut me off.
你没有必要打断我
Dollhouse, please.
先把娃娃屋拿出来再说
Okay. Yeah, in a minute.
好的  马上就好
You know what you should do?
你知道该怎么做吗
March right over there
去他家找他
and wave that trophy in his stupid eco face.
向他炫耀一下你的奖杯
No. You think?
不是吧  你真这么想吗
Yes. Those people are so annoying.
没错  这些人烦死了
There's this girl at my school
我们学校有个女生
who was all over me about my boots 'cause they're leather.
一直指责我说我的靴子是皮的
Meanwhile, she's wearing Crocs,
可她自己还穿"鳄鱼牌"[洞洞鞋]
like those aren't endangered.
好像那就没有濒临灭绝一样
You know what? I am gonna do that.
你知道么  我就要那么做
Show him to out-green me.
让他知道我有多环保
- Okay. Oh, no. - Oh, no.
-好吧  不  -不
All right, those are blowing into his yard.
都吹到他的院子里了
That is -- okay, that's definitely gonna hurt my case.
这  这绝对对我不利
Uh, you pick these up.
你把这些捡起来
I'm gonna go get the trophy. Lily, help her.
我去拿奖杯  莉莉  你帮她捡
I heard that "recycled child" comment.
我听到你说"回收小孩"的话了
Thanks to your little flask,
多谢你的酒瓶
now the teacher thinks I'm a burnout.
现在老师认为我是个酒鬼
Football game.
橄榄球赛
- What are you doing? - You can do this now.
-你在干吗  -现在可以语音搜索了
I saw it in a commercial.
我在广告上看到的
Not with that phone.
那款手机做不到
You might as well say it into your wallet.
跟对着钱包说效果一样
Come on. We're gonna be late for math.
快点  我们要赶不上数学课了
I'm not going to any more boring classes.
我不会再去那些无聊的课了
You're just gonna cut?
你要半途而废吗
No,I'm just not gonna go because I'm in my 60s.
不  不去上课是因为我已经六十多了
Teacher's lounge.
教师休息室
They got a TV in here.
这里有台电视机
- We can't go in the teacher's lounge. - Why not?
-我们不能去教师休息室  -为什么不
- Um, it's for teachers only. - You're a teacher.
-因为那是老师专用的  -你就是老师
Right now, you're teaching me how to be a little bitch.
你现在就在教我怎么做个小怨妇
Jay, don't. Jay.
杰  不要  杰
Jay!
杰
So, when do you think you'll be making your decision?
您大概什么时候做决定呢
Oh, sometime in the next week or so.
下周左右吧
Oh, take your time. It would be rude to rush you.
慢慢来  逼您做决定是不礼貌的
Not as rude as interrupting two people
在别人谈话的时候插嘴
in the middle of a conversation.
更没礼貌
Well, actually, I'll go.
实际上我得走了
I'm gonna go grab some coffee.
我要喝点咖啡
Good idea because those cupcakes look very dry.
就是  那些蛋糕看起来就很干
Okay. This is unbelievable.
这简直让人难以置信
They just gave me four books on applying to top colleges.
他们刚给了我四本关于申请名校的书
When am I gonna have time to read all this?
我哪来的时间读完这些
Oh, my gosh. I'm so sorry.
天啊  真对不起
I didn't see you there. Come on, girls.
我没看到你  快来吧  各位
Oh, she's so mean.
她超过分的
- Everybody sees me. - Who was that?
-怎么可能有人注意不到我  -她是谁
Dr. Dooda Dada.
多达・达达医生
She thinks that she can flirt her son all the way to Washington,
她以为可以靠色诱老师帮她儿子去华盛顿
but I'm gonna take her down.
我不会让她得逞的
I would love to chat, but I got to get to A.P. Calc.
我很想跟你聊  可我得去微积分课
Physical education is a critical part of every school day.
体育课是学校生活的重要部分
As we develop the mind, so we must the body.
我们学习知识的同时  也应该锻炼身体
This begins with good nutrition, uh, physical activity,
首先需要保证营养  勤做运动
sportsmanship, and attention to personal hygiene.
培养体育精神以及注重个人卫生
No, please, please, please don't go.
不  拜托你们不要走
I know this is boring, but this isn't my idea.
我知道这很无聊  可这不是我安排的
I wanted to play a spirited game of dodgeball, but --
我本来想组织一场躲避球大赛  可是
That sounds fun. I'll play dodgeball.
听起来很有趣  我要玩躲避球
I'll play, too.
我也要玩
Anything's got to be better than this.
任何东西都比讲这些有意思
Oh, well, you know what?
知道吗
We're really not supposed to, but you know what?
我们真的不应该那么做  可是知道吗
Hey, guys, listen to this. My name's Cam.
各位  听着  我叫小卡
I'm the sheriff of Dodge...ball.
是"多比"镇警官  其实是"躲避"球
Okay, you guys are the Hatfields.
你们是哈特菲尔德队
You are the McCoys.
你们是麦考伊队
Mr. Mandelbaum, I'd like you to stay seated.
曼德尔鲍姆先生  请您继续坐着
You're gonna be our referee.
您来做我们的裁判就好
All right, everybody, let's dodgeball!
好了  各位  躲避球大赛开始
Dodgeball was a smash.
躲避球比赛精彩极了
Dr. Donna and Gloria were like two assassins
唐娜医生和歌洛莉亚像两个刺客
just picking off their victims one by one.
把他们的目标一个一个干掉
Okay, last two dodgeballers.
终极躲避球对决
Are you ready?
准备好了吗
Yes.
准备好了
Oh, I'm so sorry.
不好意思
I'm going to kill you!
我要杀了你
Gloria, Gloria, Gloria, don't!
歌洛莉亚  歌洛莉亚不要激动
Ow! My eye! I don't understand you!
我的眼睛  你们怎么能这样
So, you like theater,
你喜欢戏剧
and you just put this fake thumb in our fries.
而你刚在薯条里放了根假拇指
Yep.
没错
I'm gonna go out on a limb here
这么说也许有点冒险
and say we're with the wrong people.
可是我们也许约错人了
Let's just switch dates and get this party started.
我们互换对象就解决问题了
What? We don't want to switch.
什么  我们不想换
Yeah. I'm not attracted to you.
我对你没兴趣
And I'm not attracted to you.
我也对你没兴趣
Wait a minute.
等等
We like all the same things, but you don't think I'm cute?
我们爱好相同但你却不喜欢我吗
I've got a thing for Latin men.
我对拉丁裔男生有好感
I like 'em dumb.
我喜欢呆一点的
- Ugh. Well, that's just offensive. - And shallow.
-这很伤人  -而且肤浅
Just because we're guys doesn't mean we don't have feelings.
我们是男生不代表我们不会受伤
Yeah. I don't feel good about this.
我觉得这不太好
It makes me feel...
让我觉得
bad.
很糟
Come on, Luke. Let's get out of here.
算了  卢克  我们走吧
Our parents aren't home.
我们的父母不在家
If you want, we'll make out with you.
如果你们愿意  我们可以和你们亲热下
I'm not proud of what happened next.
接下来发生的事我并不引以为豪
I am.
我觉得很好
He's not home.
他不在家
How's the cleanup going?
你打扫得怎样了
Well, I think I got most of them.
我觉得大部分搞定了
You've been at this a while.
你搞了这么久
How come you only have like eight peanuts?
怎么只捡了八个塑料球呢
Instead of carrying them around,
我只是没有把它们抱着到处走
I made a huge pile right over th--
我把它们都堆在那里
- Again?! - Geez. They're everywhere.
-又来  -天哪  到处都是
Oh, god. No! Bird!
天哪  不  有只鸟
Aah! Oh, no!
不要啊
Oh, no! No, no, no, no, no!
不  不  不  不
Oh, no! What is that smell?!
不  这是什么味道
It smells like french fries!
闻起来像炸薯条
It's biodiesel. Can you plug it up?
这是生物柴油  你能把它塞起来吗
- Oh, what? With what? Popcorn? - Oh, geez. Oh, god.
-用什么塞  爆米花吗  -天哪
No! My boots! This is a disaster!
不  我的靴子  真是场灾难
Save the seals!
保护海豹
What -- what -- what -- what the hell?
什么  什么情况
What did you do?
你们做了什么
Uh, I won a green award.
我赢过一座环保奖杯
That's what.
就是这样
You think you can get this thing to work?
你确定你能修好这东西吗
Hey, you're supposed to be the lookout.
你应该去放哨的
What if somebody walks in?
有人进来了怎么办
Gee, they'll call my parents.
他们会打给我父母
Hey! Look! You did it!
看  你成功了
Yeah, it's not that big of a deal.
是啊  不是很复杂
Listen, I'm gonna get back to class.
听着  我要回课堂了
Before you go, let me ask you a question.
你走之前  我有个问题想问你
How do you know how to do all this stuff?
你怎么会这么擅长修理东西呢
Back in high school, I was in the A.V. Club.
高中时  我是影音俱乐部的
We did all kinds of crazy things.
我们做过很多疯狂的事情
One year, we hid a microphone in the gym.
有一年  我们在体育馆藏了一台麦克风
We could totally hear everything that was going on at prom.
毕业舞会发生的事情我们都能听到
I used to make fun of guys like you.
我曾经取笑过你们这种人
This is pretty cool.
但这很酷
Really?
真的吗
You think this is cool...
你觉得这就算酷了
First down! All right.
第一次进攻  好样的
Best open house ever.
史上最棒的学校开放日
It's all gravy when you're in the A.V.
在影音俱乐部里一切都轻而易举
Admit it -- doesn't it feel good
承认吧  打破些规则
to break a few rules,
游走在制度边缘
take a walk on the wild side?
是不是感觉挺好
- You're welcome. - No, you're welcome.
-不用谢  -不  是你不用谢
I'm the one who set this whole thing up.
这些都是我搞的
Let's just say we make a good team.
不如说我们配合得不错吧
To us.
敬我们
There he goes. There he goes.
他进攻了  进攻了
Come on, come on! Come on!
上啊  上啊  上啊
Come on! Yeah!
上啊  漂亮
I've been like this for as long as I can remember.
从我记事起我就是这个样子了
Can you give me an example?
能给我举个例子吗
Well, when I was little,
在我很小的时候
I was in a spelling team at school
是拼写队的成员
and I really wanted to win.
我真的很想赢
I don't know why. There was no prize.
我也不知道为什么  也没有奖励
No one cared.
没人在乎
My parents didn't even know I was in it.
我父母甚至都不知道我参加了
I just felt this weight on my shoulders,
我只是觉得肩上有这样的责任
like if I lost, I'd...I don't know.
就好像如果输了  我会  我也不知道
- I just had to win. - And did you?
-我就是必须要赢  -那你赢了吗
Yep. Know what the winning word was?
是的  你知道决胜的词是什么吗
Responsibility.
责任
Is that what you feel?
你是那么想的吗
A responsibility to win all the time?
一直有着需要赢的责任
To always be the best?
永远要做最好的
That's one way to put it.
你可以这么说
And this responsibility -- where does it come from?
这种责任  从哪里来
I'm not sure. It's just...there.
我也不知道  它就自然存在了
So it's an internal pressure.
所以这是种内部压力
Kind of.
算是吧
I mean, once you start overachieving,
一旦你做得超过预期了
people expect things from you.
人们就开始对你有所期待
Like what people?
人们是谁
You know, the world...
就是  全世界
Teachers, parents, other kids.
老师  家长  其他孩子
It's not all internal.
也不完全是内部的
Don't get me wrong.
别误会
I like the way I'm wired.
我喜欢这种紧张的状态
It's what's going to get me into a good school.
只有这样我才能上好学校
It's what makes me who I am.
这才是我
And how is that -- being who you are?
那感觉怎么样  做你自己
I don't know.
我不知道
Mostly good.
大多数时候还不错
A little exhausting.
有点累
Sometimes hard.
有时候很艰难
I guess there's your answer.
我觉得这就是你想要的答案吧
It's hard being me.
做我自己很难
Tell me a little more about your family.
再跟我说说你的家庭
They're pretty normal, I guess.
就是个很普通的家庭
I'm not like any of them,
我跟他们都不太一样
- But that doesn't really bother me. - Ever?
-但这对我没什么困扰  -从来没有吗
Only when they say things like "Alex, you study too much"
除非他们说"艾丽克斯  你太刻苦了"
or "Don't freak out" or "Go do something fun."
或是"别紧张"  "去玩玩"之类的
So, your siblings--
就是说你的兄弟姐妹
they don't experience the same pressures you do.
他们并没有你那样的压力
Oh, god, no. They don't care about school.
天呐  当然没有  他们才不在乎学业
Hmm. Why do you think that is?
你觉得原因是什么呢
I mean, you all grew up in the same house
你们都在同一屋檐下长大
with the same parents, yet you're the only one
有着同样的父母  而你却是唯一
who feels this enormous pressure
为了达到高标准
to achieve at such a high level.
而感到巨大压力的人
Why do we even have to talk about my family?
为什么要谈论我的家人
They don't have anything to do with this.
他们跟这事没关系
They don't get me.
他们不懂我
How's that feel?
这种感觉如何
- I don't know. - You're a smart girl.
-不知道  -你很聪明
- Try a little harder. - I said I don't know.
-再好好想想  -我说了不知道
I feel...
我感觉
kind of alone.
有点孤单
I realize our juniors are busy with SATs, so as a rule,
我知道孩子们都忙着准备入学考试
I only give two hours of homework a night.
所以我每晚只布置两个小时的作业量
- Two hours? - Our students are highly advanced.
-两个小时啊  -我们的学生非常棒
It's nothing they can't handle.
他们完全应付得来
You know, I'm-- I'm sure they can.
我相信他们可以
It's just that if they have two hours in this class
只是说他们要上两小时的课
and they have an hour for A.P. Bio
还要上一小时的生物课
and an hour and a half for, um, advanced lit
还有一个半小时的文学课
and-- hang on one second.
再加上  稍等
Let me just do this on the board,
我要写在板子上
'cause then it's-- um, we got 2 and 1 and 1.5
两小时一小时再加一个半小时
and then another, uh, hour and a half
之后还有一个半小时
for A.P. History-- gives us...
历史课  算下来
- It's 6. - Yes!
-六小时  -没错
Nina, I was getting there.
妮娜  我就要算出来了
Thank you! Thank you so much!
谢谢  非常感谢
If I could just have a second to think
要是你打字没那么大声
without all the tippy-tappy typing.
我就能静下心来计算了
6.
六小时
Well, I hope you're happy.
这下你们高兴了吧
You've ruined dodgeball for everyone.
你们毁了大家的躲避球赛
She was the one who threw that ball in my face.
是她把球扔到我脸上的
Only because you threw yourself at Mr. Ingram.
那是因为你色诱英格拉姆老师
Okay, ladies, please.
拜托  女士们
Can't you see what's going on here?
你们看不出你们在干什么吗
You both just want what's best for your kids.
你们都只是想为孩子争取最好的机会
I need to get this trip for Wesley.
我得帮韦斯利争取到这次旅行
I'm tired of him being so mad at me all the time.
我不想再看到他每次都对我生气
Why is he mad?
他为什么生气
Oh, he blames me for the divorce.
他认为我和他爸离婚是我的错
His father will always be the hero.
他爸爸总是那个好人
It's hard to blame someone who's never there.
不在身边的人总是不会被责怪
Now, can't you relate to that?
难道你不能理解吗
It will get better.
会好起来的
Kids always figure out who's really there for them.
孩子们会明白谁是真正为他们好的
Again, we're very sorry about the projector.
对投影仪的事再次表示抱歉
I'll send a check on Monday.
我周一会寄来支票
- Hi, honey. - I got in trouble.
-亲爱的  -我惹事了
Whatever she did, add it to my tab.
她的事都记到我的帐上
- All right, let's do this. - No. No, no, no.
-好吧  来吧  -不不
Not you two, just you. Come on, sheriff.
不是你俩  就你  来吧  警长
Oh, hey, honey. How did it go?
亲爱的  怎么样
Good. And I made another session for next week.
挺好的  下周继续
How was the open house?
学校开放日怎么样
Wow. So intense.
非常紧张
I had no idea the kind of pressure you're under.
我都不知道你承受了那么大的压力
Honey, I was just you for two hours.
亲爱的  我只在学校体验了两个小时
I could barely hold it together.
就已经快受不了了
I don't know how you don't have a meltdown every day.
你没有每天情绪失控真是太了不起了
- I... - Oh, honey.
-我  -亲爱的
Sweetie, what? Did I say something?
宝贝  怎么了  是我说了什么吗
Yes.
是的
Thank you.
谢谢
Okay.
没事
Again, I am so sorry.
再次抱歉
I-I guess, in retrospect, it was a little crazy
现在想来  我过来向你炫耀
that I wanted to show you my state bar association award.
我的州律师协会奖  实在有点疯狂
Stop.
别说了
And it's possible I come on a little too strong.
可能是我太过激了
No. No, no.
不不不
I like to think that I'm greener than I am,
我以为我很环保
but maybe I just want the credit
但也许我只是想
without doing all the hard work that you do.
不像你那样卖力气就得到赞赏
Well, you're right-- it is hard,
你说得对  是很不容易
but, you know, it's also alienating.
但也会遭到孤立
You know, no one wants to be friends with me.
没人想跟我交朋友
I-I can't tell you the last time
我都不记得上次请别人
I had people over for dinner,
来家里吃饭是什么时候了
which is probably a good thing.
也许这是好事
You know, with solar power,
你知道太阳能嘛
it takes four days to roast a chicken.
需要四天的时间才能烤熟一只鸡
- Really? - If you want it cooked all the way through, yeah.
-真的吗  -如果你想全熟的话
You know I had salmonella three times?
知道我得过三次沙门氏菌病吗
If you want to come over to our house for dinner,
你可以来我家吃饭
- we kind of owe you. - You can play with my dollhouse.
-我们欠你的  -你可以玩我的娃娃屋
Yeah?
真的吗
Does it made from sustainable materials?
那是可持续材料做的吗
Forget it.
当我没说